Guide to the Educational Cooperative Publishing Company of Montana records 1937-1967
Montana Historical Society
Educational Cooperative Publishing Company of Montana records
1937-1967
Montana Historical Society Archives
MC 40
Educational Cooperative Publishing Company of Montana
7 linear feet of shelf space
The People's Voice was a weekly newspaper published in Helena, Montana, by H.S. "Cap" Bruce, and later by Harry L. Billings. Records consist primarily of general correspondence (1937-1966); and subject files (1930s-1960s) on a wide variety of topics, including Montana politics, farmers unions, labor, state government, and public utilities.
The People's Voice, a cooperative newspaper, was founded in 1939, by H.S. "Cap" Bruce with the backing of farm coop and labor leaders. Bruce, a veteran newspaperman, saw the need for an independent state-wide paper after the established press failed to report adequately on the 1937 state legislature's defeat of liberal measures. Bruce's newly formed Educational Co-operative Publishing Company bought a press and, in December 1939, began publication of The People's Voice. The Voice covered both local and national issues, taking strong stands on the issues of public power, protection of public lands, establishment of farmers' cooperatives, the abolition of capital punishment, minimum wage, and other labor union concerns. In spite of its small circulation, the paper's political influence was considerable. In November 1948, associate editor Harry L. Billings, assisted by his wife Gretchen, succeeded Bruce as managing editor. After Billings retired in 1968, Bennett Hansen took over the Voice's management, but financial difficulties forced the paper to cease publication shortly thereafter.
The records include general correspondence (composed in part of incoming and outgoing correspondence without reciprocal response), pertaining to a wide range of political issues. The majority of correspondence during the period of Billings' editorship was arranged in the various subject files. There are also a few financial, legal, and organizational records of the company.
Arranged by series
Collection open for research.
Acquisition information available upon request
Photographs transferred to Photo Archives. See inventory below for more information.
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the Montana Historical Society Archives catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search under these terms.
Educational Cooperative Publishing Company of Montana
Butte (Mont.)--Industries--Mines and mineral resources; Helena (Mont.)--Periodicals; Helena (Mont.)--Politics and government; Marias River Valley (Mont.); Red Lodge (Mont.)
Agriculture--Societies, etc.--Montana; Electric power--Montana; Electric utilities--Montana--Law and Legislation; Labor and laboring classes--Montana; Newspaper publishing--Montana; Petroleum industry and trade--Montana; Public utilities--Montana--Regulation; Strikes and lockouts--Copper mining; Trials (murder)--Montana; Universities and Colleges--Montana; Veterans--Societies, etc
Montana; Publishers and Publishing
Detailed Description of the Collection
The following section contains a detailed listing of the materials in the collection
- General Correspondence
  - A.A. Alvord, 1937 (Box-folder 1 / 1)
  - A (correspondents include Carl Ahlgreen; Anaconda labor unions; A.E. Anderson), 1937 (Box-folder 1 / 2)
  - M.K. Beadle, 1937 (Box-folder 1 / 3)
  - Robert Brown, 1937 (Box-folder 1 / 4)
  - Ernest Burns, 1937 (Box-folder 1 / 5)
  - B (correspondents include Sam Bechtold; Edward Bloom; Harry Boullion; Carl Bowlds; Bozeman labor unions; A.N. Brooks; Butte Miners Union #1), 1937 (Box-folder 1 / 6)
  - Clarence Chamberlain, 1937 (Box-folder 1 / 7)
  - E.W. Chapman, 1937 (Box-folder 1 / 8)
  - O.F. Clarke, 1937 (Box-folder 1 / 9)
  - C-D (correspondents include Cascade County Trades and Labor Assembly; Clifford G. Cate; Tom D. Caverly; John Clark; F.L. Darland; Frank B. Dexter), 1937 (Box-folder 1 / 10-11)
  - Leif Erickson, 1937 (Box-folder 1 / 12)
  - E (correspondents include Hugh Egan), 1937 (Box-folder 1 / 13)
  - Farmers Union (Farmers Educational and Co-operative Union of America), 1937 (Box-folder 1 / 14)
  - Farmers Union: local offices, 1937 (Box-folder 1 / 15)
  - Farmers Union Central Exchange, 1937 (Box-folder 1 / 16)
  - Farmers Union Grain Terminal Association, 1937 (Box-folder 1 / 17)
  - Stanley J. Fenton, 1937 (Box-folder 1 / 18)
  - Frank Finnegan, 1937 (Box-folder 1 / 19)
  - F (correspondents include Farm Labor Council; Harrison J. Freebourn; L.D. French), 1937 (Box-folder 1 / 20)
  - W.S. Good, 1937 (Box-folder 1 / 21)
  - G (correspondents include Frank A. Gallagher; J.B. Garrison; William E. Grove), 1937 (Box-folder 1 / 22)
  - H.H. Hess, 1937 (Box-folder 1 / 23)
  - H-J (correspondents include O.K. Hansen; Hardin labor unions; Havre labor unions; Helena labor unions; Thomas Horsford; Oscar Horsford; W.G. Hunter; Art H. Jones), 1937 (Box-folder 1 / 24-26)
  - A.E. Kathan, 1937 (Box-folder 1 / 27)
  - K (correspondents include J.G. Kalbus; Mrs. J.H. Keenan; E.R. Kindler; Chester Kinsey; Albert H. Kruse), 1937 (Box-folder 1 / 28)
  - Joe Larson, 1937 (Box-folder 1 / 29)
  - Gonius Laursen, 1937 (Box-folder 1 / 30)
  - L (correspondents include H.A. Lambert; Edward P. Leonard; Howard M. Lyman), 1937 (Box-folder 1 / 31)
  - Archie McLeod, 1937 (Box-folder 1 / 32)
  - William McMurphy, 1937 (Box-folder 1 / 33)
  - Mc (correspondents include M.A. McClain; George S. McKenna), 1937 (Box-folder 1 / 34)
  - Robert W. Mackie, 1937 (Box-folder 1 / 35)
  - D.L. Manning, 1937 (Box-folder 1 / 36)
  - James W. Masterson, 1937 (Box-folder 1 / 37)
  - Ambrose G. Measure, 1937 (Box-folder 1 / 38)
  - F.C. Metzger, 1937 (Box-folder 1 / 39)
  - Lee Metcalf, 1937 (Box-folder 1 / 40)
  - E.G. Miller, 1937 (Box-folder 1 / 41)
  - George Monahan, 1937 (Box-folder 1 / 42)
  - M (correspondents include Paul Mathis; Ted Maxwell; Mrs. Frank Meldrum; Sam W. Mitchell; George H. Montgomery), 1937 (Box-folder 1 / 43)
  - William J. Nelson, 1937 (Box-folder 2 / 1)
  - N (correspondents include Edward J. Nichols; Northern Montana Beetgrowers' Association), 1937 (Box-folder 2 / 2)
  - Edward O'Byrne, 1937 (Box-folder 2 / 3)
  - O (correspondents include S.W. Oliver; Curtis B. Owen), 1937 (Box-folder 2 / 4)
  - J.M. Peterson, 1937 (Box-folder 2 / 5)
  - N.A. Peterson, 1937 (Box-folder 2 / 6)
  - P.C. Peterson, 1937 (Box-folder 2 / 7)
  - William J. Priest, 1937 (Box-folder 2 / 8)
  - P-R (correspondents include G.E. Paulson; Pearl Assurance Company; William Poppler; R.H. Rebal; W.H. Reed; A.F. Robson; George W. Ruffcorn), 1937 (Box-folder 2 / 9-11)
  - John Severovic, 1937 (Box-folder 2 / 12)
  - Bentley Sinclair, 1937 (Box-folder 2 / 13)
  - Sam Spiegel, 1937 (Box-folder 2 / 14)
  - Hays Starks, 1937 (Box-folder 2 / 15)
  - S-T (correspondents include Mary Sathre; Melvin L. Schneider; Albert Simons; T.P. Taylor), 1937 (Box-folder 2 / 16-17)
  - United Mine Workers of America, 1937 (Box-folder 2 / 18)
  - U-V (correspondents include U.S. Resettlement Administration; Joseph Vanek), 1937 (Box-folder 2 / 19-20)
  - E.J. Wight, 1937 (Box-folder 2 / 21)
  - Charles H. Wolff, 1937 (Box-folder 2 / 22)
  - W, 1937 (Box-folder 2 / 23)
  - Form letter thanking subscribers to stock of company, 1937 (Box-folder 2 / 24)
  - A.E. Anderson, 1938 (Box-folder 2 / 25)
  - Robert Brown, 1938 (Box-folder 2 / 26)
  - Ernest Burns, 1938 (Box-folder 2 / 27)
  - B (correspondents include Graeme B. Baker; Arthur Beckstrom; F.E. Bergren; Peter Berimen; Blaine County Farmers Union; Patricia Brennan), 1938 (Box-folder 2 / 28)
  - Clarence Chamberlain, 1938 (Box-folder 2 / 29)
  - O.F. Clarke, 1938 (Box-folder 2 / 30)
  - Communist Party of the United States of America, Butte District, 1938 (Box-folder 2 / 31)
  - C (correspondents include Cascade County Trades and Labor Assembly; Frank Cimrhakl [sp?]; Margaret Colton; Thomas C. Colton, 1938 (Box-folder 2 / 32)
  - Elmer Denaney, 1938 (Box-folder 2 / 33)
  - H.O. Ekern, 1938 (Box-folder 2 / 34)
  - Leif Erickson, 1938 (Box-folder 2 / 35)
  - Farmers Union (Farmers Educational and Co-operative Union of America), 1938 (Box-folder 2 / 36)
  - Farmers Union: local offices, 1938 (Box-folder 2 / 37)
  - Farmers Union Central Exchange, 1938 (Box-folder 2 / 38)
  - F-G (correspondents include Farmers Union Elevator Company; Farmers Union Grain Terminal Association; Farmers Union Oil Company; Arlie Foor; Great Falls Mill and Smeltermen's Union #16), 1938 (Box-folder 2 / 39-40)
  - H.H. Hess, 1938 (Box-folder 2 / 41)
  - H-L (correspondents include Mark Hampton; R.A. Harbo; International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers #122; International Union of Operating Engineers #377; J.B.C. Knight; Labor; Richard Lake; H.A. Lambert; Mina S. Lampell; Laundry Workers, Cleaners and Dyers #19; O.B. Lovely; Howard M. Lyman), 1938 (Box-folder 2 / 42-45)
  - D.L. Manning, 1938 (Box-folder 2 / 46)
  - James E. Murray, 1938 (Box-folder 2 / 47)
  - M (correspondents include M.A. McClain; George S. McKenna; Guy Miller; Montana Workers' Alliance; George H. Montgomery), 1938 (Box-folder 2 / 48)
  - Edward O'Byrne, 1938 (Box-folder 2 / 49)
  - William J. Priest, 1938 (Box-folder 2 / 50)
  - P-Z (correspondents include Donald C. Peterson; Bert Replogle; A.W. Ricker; John Severovic; H.S. Sylvester; Teton County Farmers Union; United Mine Workers of America; U.S. Farm Security Administration; Edith H. Wall; C.L. Waring; Joe Zuncich), 1938 (Box-folder 2 / 51-57)
  - A-B (correspondents include Walter Aitken; Minnie Beadle; Albert V. Bielles; Butte Miners Union #1), 1939 (Box-folder 2 / 58-59)
  - E.B. Coolidge, 1939 (Box-folder 2 / 60)
  - C-E (correspondents include Cascade County Trades and Labor Assembly; Community Hospital [cooperative hospital in Elk City, Oklahoma]; Cut Bank Pioneer Press; H.O. Ekern), 1939 (Box-folder 2 / 61-62)
  - Farmers Union (Farmers Educational and Co-operative Union of America), 1939 (Box-folder 2 / 63)
  - Farmers Union: local offices, 1939 (Box-folder 2 / 64)
  - Farmers Union Central Exchange, 1939 (Box-folder 2 / 65)
  - Farmers Union Grain Terminal Association, 1939 (Box-folder 2 / 66)
  - F (correspondents include Farmers Union Market, Nashua; Farmers Union Oil Company; Federated Press news service; Arlie Foor), 1939 (Box-folder 2 / 67)
  - W.S. Good, 1939 (Box-folder 2 / 68)
  - G-L (correspondents include Leo Garnet re events in Finland; Angeline Golubin; A.I. Harris; Helena Postmaster; Ben Hollenback; International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers; International Labor Defense enclosing poem by Kyle Pugh; Mrs. Lars Kalsta; H.A. Lambert; Jerome Locke), 1939 (Box-folder 2 / 69-73)
  - D.L. Manning, 1939 (Box-folder 2 / 74)
  - James E. Murray, 1939 (Box-folder 2 / 75)
  - M (correspondents include W.Y. Maloney; F.C. Metzger; Montana Farmers Union Mutual Fire Insurance Company; Montana Progressive Council; Montana State University Teachers Union), 1939 (Box-folder 2 / 76)
  - National Youth Administration (Richard Lake), 1939 (Box-folder 3 / 1)
  - Edward O'Byrne, 1939 (Box-folder 3 / 2)
  - P-R (correspondents include Frank Polutnik; Red Lodge Workers' Alliance), 1939 (Box-folder 3 / 3-4)
  - Sam Spiegel, 1939 (Box-folder 3 / 5)
  - S-Y (correspondents include Sheep Shearers' Union of North America #1; G.C. Threet; U.S. Farm Credit Administration; U.S. Farm Security Administration; United Mine Workers of America; Valier Cooperative Society; Thomas H. Wright; Yellowstone County Trades and Labor Assembly), 1939 (Box-folder 3 / 6-11)
  - A (correspondents include Walter Aitken; Allied Printing Trades Council; American Federation of Teachers; American Youth Congress re Emergency Peace Mobilization; Parker T. Anderson; Ella V. Archer), 1940 (Box-folder 3 / 12)
  - John W. Bonner, 1940 (Box-folder 3 / 13)
  - B (correspondents include Charles Banderob; M.J. Beck; Peter Bokma; Brandtjen and Kluge re printing press; A.R. Brewer; O.A. Brotherman; Gottlieb Brummer; Butte Miners Union #1; L.L. Buchanan; Harry L. Burns), 1940 (Box-folder 3 / 14)
  - Paul Cannon, 1940 (Box-folder 3 / 15)
  - E.B. Coolidge, 1940 (Box-folder 3 / 16)
  - C-E (correspondents include Florence Cady; Cascade County Trades and Labor Assembly; Thomas C. Colton; Walter P. Coombs; G.W. Crossley; F.L. Darland; Jasper DeDobbeleer; C.V. Dooley; I.E. Duncan; Hugh Egan; H.O. Ekern; Frank E. Ellsworth; Equity Cooperative Association of Harlem), 1940 (Box-folder 3 / 17-19)
  - Farmers Union (Farmers Educational and Co-operative Union of America), 1940 (Box-folder 3 / 20)
  - Farmers Union: local offices, 1940 (Box-folder 3 / 21)
  - Farmers Union Central Exchange, 1940 (Box-folder 3 / 22)
  - Farmers Union Grain Terminal Association, 1940 (Box-folder 3 / 23)
  - Frank Finnegan, 1940 (Box-folder 3 / 24)
  - Sam C. Ford, 1940 (Box-folder 3 / 25)
  - F (correspondents include Farmer Labor Political Federation; Farmers Union Elevator Company; Farmers Union Live Stock Commission Company; Farmers Union Oil Company; Farmers Union Trading Company; Federal Labor Union #18741; Flathead Voters Council; Mary E. Friday), 1940 (Box-folder 3 / 26)
  - W.S. Good, 1940 (Box-folder 3 / 27)
  - G, 1940 (Box-folder 3 / 28)
  - H.H. Hess, 1940 (Box-folder 3 / 29)
  - H-J (correspondents include Herbert H. Haight; Oscar Horsford; C.S. Horton; George E. Hurd; Idaho Public Utilities Commission; Bertina Johnson), 1940 (Box-folder 3 / 30-32)
  - [A.E.] Kathan-for-Governor Club, 1940 (Box-folder 3 / 33)
  - K-L (correspondents include Kalispell Trades and Labor Council; J.C. Keenan; R.D. Kenney; The Kenosha Labor; Chester Kinsey; George J. Ladwig; Lake County Farmers Union Egg Cooperative; Richard Lake; H.A. Lambert; A.F. Lamey; Jerome G. Locke; Jens L. Larson; Howard M. Lyman), 1940 (Box-folder 3 / 34-35)
  - Mc (correspondents include John H. McGuffey; J.C. McIntire; J.E. McKenna), 1940 (Box-folder 3 / 36)
  - D.L. Manning, 1940 (Box-folder 3 / 37)
  - Mike Mansfield, 1940 (Box-folder 3 / 38)
  - F.C. Metzger, 1940 (Box-folder 3 / 39)
  - James E. Murray, 1940 (Box-folder 3 / 40)
  - M-N (correspondents include Montana Industrial Accident Board; Montana Licensed Liquor Dealers Association; Montana Progressive Club; Montana Superintendent of Public Instruction Ruth Reardon; Margaret Nagle; A.L. Nicholls; Catherine Nutterville), 1940 (Box-folder 3 / 41-42)
  - Edward O'Byrne, 1940 (Box-folder 3 / 43)
  - O (correspondents include Oscar L. Olvrud), 1940 (Box-folder 3 / 44)
  - J.M. Peterson, 1940 (Box-folder 3 / 45)
  - P-R (correspondents include [West] Powell for Railroad Commissioner Club; Bert Replogle; Peter Rorvik; William W. Ruffcorn), 1940 (Box-folder 3 / 46-47)
  - Sam Spiegel, 1940 (Box-folder 3 / 48)
  - S-U (correspondents include E.B. Shipman; W.H. Smith; J.T. Sparling; Spokane Bank for Cooperatives; J.L. Strong; Townsend National Recovery Plan; U.S. Agricultural Adjustment Administration; U.S. Post Office Dept.), 1940 (Box-folder 3 / 49-51)
  - Burton K. Wheeler, 1940 (Box-folder 3 / 52)
  - W-Y (correspondents include Western Newspaper Union; Bon Whealdon; John Q. Wilson; Yellowstone County Trades and Labor Assembly; Frank W. Young), 1940 (Box-folder 3 / 53-54)
  - Unidentified and anonymous, 1940 (Box-folder 3 / 55)
  - A-B (correspondents include Walter Aitken; Association for Maintenance of Free Enterprise in Montana; F.A. Banderob; Barber Telephone Company; Brandjen and Kluge; Stanley Brooks; Butte Youth Council), 1941 (Box-folder 4 / 1-2)
  - E.B. Coolidge, 1941 (Box-folder 4 / 3)
  - C-E (correspondents include Chinese Relief Committee; Communist Party of the United States of America, Montana District; Walter P. Coombs; Wayne Coster; Gordon Crandell; F.L. Darland; Gladys E. Erhard), 1941 (Box-folder 4 / 4-6)
  - Farmers Union (Farmers Educational and Co-operative Union of America), 1941 (Box-folder 4 / 7)
  - Farmers Union: local offices, 1941 (Box-folder 4 / 8)
  - Farmers Union Central Exchange, 1941 (Box-folder 4 / 9)
  - Farmers Union Grain Terminal Association, 1941 (Box-folder 4 / 10)
  - Sam C. Ford, 1941 (Box-folder 4 / 11)
  - F (correspondents include Farmers Co-op Oil and Supply Company; Farmers Union Education Service; Farmers Union Grain Company; Farmers Union Live Stock Commission Company; Farmers Union Oil Company), 1941 (Box-folder 4 / 12)
  - W.S. Good, 1941 (Box-folder 4 / 13)
  - G-J (correspondents include P.J. Gilfeather; C.S. Horton; International Association of Operating Engineers #377; International Union of Mine, Mill and Smelter Workers Committee on Cooperation; Berger Johnson), 1941 (Box-folder 4 / 14-17)
  - A.E. Kathan, 1941 (Box-folder 4 / 18)
  - K-Mc (correspondents include Elia Kaneff; L.F. King; League for Efficiency in Government; Jerome G. Locke; Rose M. Lucero; Hobart McKean; George S. McKenna), 1941 (Box-folder 4 / 19-21)
  - Mike Mansfield, 1941 (Box-folder 4 / 22)
  - M-N (correspondents include Molt Farmers Elevator Company; Northwest Cooperative Society), 1941 (Box-folder 4 / 23-24)
  - William J. Priest, 1941 (Box-folder 4 / 25)
  - P-R (correspondents include Power Farmers Elevator Company; John Reagen re National Youth Administration programs; Peter Rorvik), 1941 (Box-folder 4 / 26-27)
  - Hays Starks, 1941 (Box-folder 4 / 28)
  - S-V (correspondents include Joseph St. Marks; E.B. Shipman; Charles E. Smith; W.H. Smith; Southern Tenant Farmers Union; John Stahlberg; Harry B. Syverud; United Pension Movement of Montana; R.F. Vanek), 1941 (Box-folder 4 / 29-32)
  - Burton K. Wheeler, 1941 (Box-folder 4 / 33)
  - W (correspondents include Western Newspaper Union; Bon Whealdon enclosing poem on Indians; S.P. Wilson), 1941 (Box-folder 4 / 34)
  - Unidentified and anonymous, 1941 (Box-folder 4 / 35)
  - Frank Finnegan, 1942 (Box-folder 4 / 36)
  - Charles P. Jacobsen, 1942 (Box-folder 4 / 37)
  - William McMurphy, 1942 (Box-folder 4 / 38)
  - James E. Murray, 1942 (Box-folder 4 / 39)
  - M (correspondents include Daniel S. McCorkle re conditions at Warm Springs State Hospital; Montana Workers Alliance; also includes May Day flyer), 1942 (Box-folder 4 / 40)
  - Park County Trades and Labor Council, 1942 (Box-folder 4 / 41)
  - V-W (correspondents include George B. Vaughan; George Wieglenda), 1942 (Box-folder 4 / 42-43)
  - Unidentified and anonymous, 1942 (Box-folder 4 / 44)
  - Miscellaneous (correspondents include William Scallon; Jay Allen; Farmers Union Oil Company; J.M. Peterson; Raymond E. Graham; Jack C. Toole; Bruce Smith; H.S. Bruce resignation from Farmers Union News; R. Bailey Stortz; Lowndes Maury Jr.; Mrs. J. Poirier), 1943-1949 (Box-folder 4 / 45)
  - Miscellaneous (correspondents include Bernice Kingsbury; Rocky Mountain Sportsmen's Association; John Jarussi; Lewistown Daily News; Gladys Jones; Joseph S. Smollack; John Morton; B.W. McDowell; Henry Horowitz; George Meany), 1950-1954 (Box-folder 4 / 46)
  - Miscellaneous (correspondents include Perry S. Melton; Lee Metcalf; Farmers Union Central Exchange; Roland Renne; Virgil Buchanan; Miles Romney; A.L. Libre; Leland Olds), 1955 (Box-folder 4 / 47)
  - Miscellaneous (correspondents include Lorene McCarthy; Mondell Bennett), 1956-1957 (Box-folder 4 / 48)
  - Leonard Kenfield, 1963 (Box-folder 4 / 49)
  - Miscellaneous (correspondents include Webb Sullivan; Lydia Sullivan), 1966 (Box-folder 4 / 50)
- Court Papers
  - Miscellaneous (includes notes and brief in State of Montana ex rel. Lewis and Clark County vs. State Board of Public Welfare re distribution of poor funds; notes on State of Montana vs. Alex Marck et al., re gambling), 1941, 1950 (Box-folder 4 / 51)
- Financial Records
  - Employee tax records (includes correspondence), 1947-1955 (Box-folder 4 / 52)
  - Miscellaneous (includes timekeeper's weekly report; inventory; cost of publishing), 1937-1955 (Box-folder 4 / 53)
- Legal Documents
  - Agreement with the Belgrade Journal to buy plant, 1938 (Box-folder 4 / 54)
- Organization
  - Miscellaneous (includes annual report; statement of ownership; notice of meeting), 1940, 1952, 1954 (Box-folder 4 / 55)
- Photographs and Printed Materials
  - List of photographs and printed material transferred to Photo Archives and Library respectively) (Box-folder 4 / 56)
- Subject Files
  - American Legion, 1947-1952 (Box-folder 5 / 1)
  - Anaconda Company, 1951 (Box-folder 5 / 2)
  - Roy E. Ayers investigation (includes testimony before Select Committee of Twenty-Sixth Legislative Assembly), 1939 (Box-folder 5 / 3)
  - Capital punishment, 1951 (Box-folder 5 / 4)
  - Columbia Valley Administration (CVA), 1949-1951 (Box-folder 5 / 5)
  - Contribution drive, 1955 (Box-folder 5 / 6)
  - Co-operatives, 1947-1967 (Box-folder 5 / 7)
  - Frank R. Dryman murder case, 1951 (Box-folder 5 / 8)
  - Elections (clippings: includes both state and national), 1940-1948 (Box-folder 5 / 9-12)
  - Elections (clippings: includes both state and national), 1948-1958 (Box-folder 6 / 1-6)
  - Elections (clippings: includes both state and national), 1958-1960 (Box-folder 7 / 1-6)
  - Elections (clippings: includes both state and national), 1964 (Box-folder 8 / 1-4)
  - Willard E. Fraser (includes correspondence, speeches, testimony before Missouri Basin Survey Commission, campaign literature, clippings), 1947-1952 (Box-folder 8 / 5)
  - Gambling (includes correspondence, clippings, petitions, court papers), 1947-1964 (Box-folder 8 / 6)
  - Gambling (clippings), 1947-1964 (Box-folder 9 / 1)
  - James Graham (deposition as Secretary of Socialist Party; obituary), 1909, 1951 (Box-folder 9 / 2)
  - John Hellman trial (re violation of anti-Communist Smith Act), 1956, 1958 (Box-folder 9 / 3)
  - Highway Commission investigations by Legislative House of Representatives (includes correspondence; House resolution; "Report of Examination, Montana State Highway Commission, December 31, 1958"; invitations for bids; transcript of hearing on state highway through Helena; hearing on alleged reprisals against Horace B. Williams; court papers; press releases; clippings), 1958-1960 (Box-folder 9 / 4-7)
  - Historical (includes donation of copies of Alfred Myers diaries to Montana State University; "The Government of Montana" by Thomas Payne), undated (Box-folder 9 / 8)
  - Hitler Bill (re HB 65 authorizing appointment and removal of state employees by Governor), 1937 (Box-folder 9 / 9)
  - John Birch Society (includes "The John Birch Society: a Soiled Slip is Showing," by Alan Cranston, re racism and anti-Semitism in the Society), 1966 (Box-folder 9 / 10)
  - John F. Kennedy assassination (clippings), 1963 (Box-folder 10 / 1)
  - Korean War and China (clippings), 1950-1951 (Box-folder 10 / 2)
  - Labor history (includes "Labor in America," term paper by John G. Billings; minutes of Montana State Federation of Labor conventions; Great Falls Typographical Union; Big Bill Haywood; "Labor Laws of the State of Montana"), 1939-1956 (Box-folder 10 / 3)
  - Labor unions (includes correspondence from local unions; form letters), 1933-1953 (Box-folder 10 / 4-5)
  - Letters of opinion ("I love you too letters"), 1948-1954 (Box-folder 10 / 6)
  - Liquor (includes "Survey of Liquor Problem in Montana," by Lucy T. McLemore; circulars by Montana Licensed Liquor Dealers Association; circular by Employees of Montana Liquor Control Board; court opinion; report of Special Investigating Committee of 26th Legislative Assembly; proposed bill to limit Liquor Control Board to wholesale business only), 1936-1955 (Box-folder 10 / 7)
  - Jerome G. Locke (re Montana MVA Association; Missouri Valley Authority; Livingston Enterprise; obituaries), 1952-1954 (Box-folder 10 / 8)
  - Marias River Irrigation Project (includes "The Marias Irrigation Project History," by W.T. Cowan; "The Big Water Gyp in Montana" re 160 acre limit on irrigated farms; Tiber Dam, etc.), 1904-1951 (Box-folder 10 / 9)